Andrew Paschall

602.615.0610 | paschallandrew@gmail.com | Phoenix, AZ

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/andrew-paschall</u> **Website:** <u>andrewpaschall.com</u>

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

I am a hands-on Salesforce Architect with 14 years of experience building web-based business applications. I specialize in technical Salesforce roles that utilize my strong presentation and facilitation skills, obtaining stakeholder acceptance by understanding and delivering the right strategic vision, and driving the difficult conversations necessary to execute business strategies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• **Proficient:** Salesforce, JavaScript, JSON, APIs, APEX, LWC, SLDS, Node.js, jQuery, SOQL, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Blockchain, Jira, Agile; **Exposure:** Mulesoft, Genesys, PHP, Java

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce Development Manager | Allstate Identity Protection | Remote

Feb 2021 – Present

- Build, lead and mentor a high-performing team of 5 Salesforce developers and system administrators
- Responsible for hands-on development of key features as well as security and code quality of the team
- Deliver live product demonstrations, technical Q&A, and roadmap communication to C-suite stakeholders
- Develop a program vision while advising and articulating program/project strategies on Salesforce platform
- Designed, deployed and tested a client-facing web portal built on Community Cloud to replace existing application at end of life; Client satisfaction increased over 40%
- Build relationships with internal/external customers, manage expectations and negotiate solutions to complex problems with both the customer and third-party partners

Salesforce Solutions Architect | <u>Allstate Identity Protection</u> | Remote

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- Technical lead for team implementing Sales/Service/Community Clouds, Lightning Experience and SSO
- Designed and developed functional solution architecture, proof-of-concepts, demos, and best practices
- Designed and implemented call center applications in Salesforce using Lightning Web Components, Custom Object design, Apex, JavaScript, SLDS, REST APIs, MuleSoft (middleware), and Genesys (telephony)
- Developed NetSuite ERP integration using Salesforce LWC, Apex, and Mulesoft to sync client payment data
- Implemented a Salesforce-native Contract Lifecycle Management solution (Conga CLM) to house all contract processes, templates, signing, maintenance and data governance on the Salesforce platform

Salesforce Solutions Architect | Shellback Semiconductor | Phoenix, AZ

Feb 2018 - Mar 2019

- Led and completed company-wide implementation of Salesforce Lightning over 6 months. Tools included
 Custom Object Design, LWC, Visualforce, Flows, Process Builder, SOQL queries, Data Loader and Apex triggers
- Built rich, highly performant applications using Lightning, Apex, and LWC JavaScript frameworks
- Lead Sales and Service process engineer for OEM Group's worldwide ERP migration
- Reduced quarterly forecast error by more than 45% via data analysis and custom Salesforce reporting

User Experience Director (UX) | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2013 - Dec 2017

- Responsible for the design, planning, configuration, programming, delivery and maintenance of the company's public website, mobile app, Salesforce CRM, and desk.com support portals
- Managed Salesforce integrations with Hubspot, Marketo and the company's proprietary technology platforms
- Salesforce developer and systems administrator for over 300 users
- Led all UX/UI design for the company's mobile/tablet application for iOS, Android and mobile web
- Automated Marketing processes via configuration and customization of Salesforce reports, dashboards, triggers and workflows

Lead Web Developer | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2011 - Apr 2013

- Redesigned, coded, and re-launched the Multivista website HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript standards; improved the company's visibility within the market and facilitated a 23% total sales increase from web leads
- Implemented open-source mapping tools to replace the company's existing proprietary application, saving more than \$40,000 per year
- Designed interactive help systems and technical training documentation, driving 30% decrease in support calls

Web Developer (Freelance Consulting) | Cleartorch, Inc. | Phoenix, AZ

Feb 2006 - Apr 2011

- Provided full-stack web development and marketing automation solutions to small to medium size companies across the U.S., primarily servicing the Financial Services, Healthcare and Higher Education industries.
- Technology included HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress and Drupal.

As a Consulting Web Developer my day-to-day activities with my clients were to:

- Conduct UX research using research tools and create project report
- Define business requirements and create user stories and personas
- Create sketch, wireframe, prototype and visual mockups
- Design and develop UI Designs with Sketch and/or Photoshop for clients
- Responsible for the accuracy and editorial integrity of text on site
- Advocate web interaction design best practices, with a focus on consistency and usability
- Conduct website performance testing and network configuration to optimized load times
- Use SEO tools and applications to assist with Google search engine rankings
- Work with backend engineers to see projects through, from conception to completion
- Set up and monitored Google AdWords advertising campaigns and conducted keyword research

EDUCATION

Certified Salesforce Platform Developer I Certified Salesforce Platform App Builder Certified Salesforce Administrator **B.A. English,** Arizona State University